promega.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to personally identifiable information collected by Promega Corporation ("Promega") through this website (this "Website") or other systems and processes under Promega's control. Although this Website provides links to third-party websites, such third-party websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Promega assumes no responsibility for the privacy or security of information you provide to any third-party through linked websites or any other means.

By using this Website, you agree that you have reviewed and understood our Terms and conditions of Use and this Privacy Policy to your full satisfaction, that you accept and are subject to our Terms and Conditions of Use of Promega Corporation Websites and this Privacy Policy, and that Promega is permitted to use your personal information as set forth below.

Our Privacy Policy is applicable and enforced for the Promega website at www.promega.com and all other websites owned by Promega. It is our intent to comply with the European Union Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC, the European Union General Data Protection Regulation and the Privacy Shield guidelines of the U.S. Department of Commerce. Please refer to the section titled "SPECIAL RULES APPLICABLE TO DATA COLLECTED OR PROCESSED IN THE EUROPEAN UNION" for additional information.

### What Personal Information We Collect

You can visit our Web sites without providing any personal information. We may collect contact information such as name, physical address, title, department, mobile or other telephone number, areas of interest and e-mail address only when you choose to submit it to us. We collect the following types of information:

  * Email address, to comply with your request that we contact you, and for other business purposes, in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity;
  * Mobile phone number, to comply with your request that we contact you, and for other business purposes, in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity;
  * Financial and payment information for billing purposes, in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity;
  * Geo-location information as is necessary to improve your customer experience, in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity;
  * Identity information for sales, marketing, customer support and technical services;
  * User name and password for the security of your user account, to comply with your request that we contact you, and for other business purposes in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity.
  * Information submitted by job applicants in order to evaluate and process your application.

Automatically Collected Information: In addition, when you visit our website, we may place tracking cookies, small computer files, on your computer to help us recognize and serve you better when you return. We keep this information to make it easier for you to utilize our site. You may delete these cookies from your computer, however, you may not be able to see or utilize portions of our Website thereafter.

**Necessary:**  
Functional session cookies required for our website to operate as intended.

**Statistical:**  
Anonymized statistical data, such as Google Analytics, increase the data quality of our website’s functionality.

**User Convenience:**  
Data that you provide to Promega that help tailor your experience on our website, such as regional and language preference.

### How We Use and Retain Your Personal Information

Promega uses your personal information as described above, to process your requests and transactions, in our legitimate interest and/or as a contractual necessity, including to offer or furnish additional products and services, personalize the types of information you receive from Promega, assess trends in the use of this Website or purchases of products or services, develop content and functionality that helps us serve our customers' needs, and improve the service and products we provide. 

Your personal information will be retained as long as is needed for us to comply with our contractual obligations, employment obligations, and other business purposes, including global legal obligations to retain data.

**Data Sharing and Transfer:**  
Promega will not use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection without first attempting to notify you via the last e-mail address we have in our records.

We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties that assist us in providing our services, carrying out your account needs or providing you with information about their services that we believe may be of interest to you. If we transfer personally identifiable information to a third-party that is acting as our agent, the third party will be required to protect the confidentiality of that information. As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets, or Promega might be acquired by another company. In any of those circumstances, personal information in our databases may be included among the transferred assets.

We may use your personally identifiable information jointly with any of our majority-owned subsidiaries so that they may assist us in achieving any of the purposes of use explained above. Promega may also use your personal information to prevent harm or injury, to prevent fraud, to protect our legal interests, to comply with or respond to legal process and to comply with applicable laws.

Resumes submitted by job applicants can be viewed by our human resources department personnel, hiring managers, employees who will be interviewing the candidate and the administrative assistants to these individuals for applicant screening and hiring purposes and for general human resources purposes.

With regard to Human Resource data received from Switzerland for use in the context of the employment relationship, Promega commits to cooperate with and comply with the advice of the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner.

#### No Third-Party Direct Marketing Use

We do not sell your data to third parties.

### Your Choices

You have several choices regarding your use of our Web sites. You can choose not to submit any personal information at all. If you do choose to submit personal data, you have the right to see and correct your data at any time by accessing your account on Promega.com You will have the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us when we first request your information. Also, in our e-mail communications you will find instructions for unsubscribing. You can request removal of your personally identifiable information from our databases by contacting us at the address listed below. To honor your request, we will need the exact information you want removed and information sufficient for us to identify the type of communication you received from us. If you have consented to our collection of your personal data, you may also withdraw your consent at any time.

### Access or Change Your Personal Information

You can access, correct, amend or delete the personal information that you have provided by logging into your Promega.com account on the Promega website. You will need to enter your username and password.

### Security

We have physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect personal information we collect online, including the use of passwords to gain access to your information. To protect your privacy and security, you must keep your password confidential. However, even with such measures, no one is able to guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not be able to bypass these measures or otherwise capture information you provide over the internet.

### Data Integrity

We will take reasonable steps to see that the personal information in our systems is relevant for its intended use and is accurate, complete and current.

### Enforcement

Promega will conduct periodic reviews of compliance to verify that this Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, complete, implemented and accessible. Any employee who violates this Privacy Policy may be subject to disciplinary action.

### Special Rules Applicable to Data Collected or Processed in the European Union

#### Privacy Shield Principles

Promega complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Promega has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.

To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

#### FTC's Enforcement and Investigation Powers

Promega is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

#### Definition of "Personal Information" and "Sensitive Personal Information"

**"Personal Information"** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his or her physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.

**"Sensitive Personal Information"** means personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information pertaining to the sex life of the individual. For the purpose of complying with the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, sensitive personal information includes ideological views or activities, information on social security measures or administrative or criminal proceedings and sanctions, which are treated outside pending proceedings.

#### Onward Transfer/Potential Liability for Third-Party Acts

Promega's accountability for data it receives pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield and subsequent transfer of that data to third parties is detailed in the Privacy Shield Principles. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, Promega requires that third parties that receive Personal Information are required to either abide by the Privacy Shield, or provide the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles. Promega may be liable if such third parties fail to meet these obligations and Promega is responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

#### Internal and External Procedures for Inquiries and Resolving Complaints

In compliance with the EU–US Privacy Shield Principles, Promega commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact Promega at:

Promega Corporation  
Privacy Manager  
Legal Department  
Promega Corporation  
2800 Woods Hollow Road  
Madison, WI 53711 USA  

Promega has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the EU Data Protection Authorities (DPAs). For privacy complaints originating from Switzerland, Promega commits to cooperate with the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner.

If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/individuals/misuse-personal-data/index_en.htm> for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel. For additional information about the arbitration process, please visit the Privacy Shield website: [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

#### Contact Point to Update, Correct, Delete or Otherwise Access Personal Information

EU individuals have the right to access personal data about them, and to limit use and disclosure of their personal data. If you wish to request access, to limit use or disclosure to, or to have your data transmitted to another organization, please email our privacy team at [privacyteam@promega.com](mailto:privacyteam@promega.com) or send a written request to the contact information provided below.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

If at any time after registering for information, your personal information changes or you change your mind about receiving information from us, send us a request specifying updated information or your new choice. Simply send your request to [privacyteam@promega.com](mailto:privacyteam@promega.com) or telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

#### Notice of the Data Storage or Processing

Any personal information collected about EU visitors via our websites is processed in the United States by Promega or by a third party acting on our behalf. When you provide personal information to Promega, you consent to the processing of your information in the United States. Our websites are hosted in the United States.

### Changes to This Policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check this Privacy Policy when you use our website to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our privacy practices. Our Privacy Policy will indicate the date it was last updated.

### Contact Points

Please contact us to learn more about our privacy practices or to change your privacy choices:

Promega Corporation  
Privacy Manager  
Legal Department  
Promega Corporation  
2800 Woods Hollow Road  
Madison, WI 53711 USA  

Last updated April 27, 2018
